[
 {
   "Question": "If we produce food that doesn’t get eaten, what else is wasted?",
   "Correct Answer": "All of the above",
   "Incorrect#1": "Water",
   "Incorrect#2": "Energy",
   "Incorrect#3": "Wildlife Habitat",
   "Fact": "Growing food and getting it to your table takes water, energy, and land, including the forests and grasslands that are home to millions of species. When food is wasted, all of those other resources are also thrown out. In addition, about 10% of all human-caused greenhouse gases contributing to climate change are linked to food waste.",
   "Tip": "TIP: Cutting down on your food waste will decrease your carbon footprint. Buy only what you will eat, and learn to love leftovers!"
 },
 {
   "Question": "What percent of food never gets eaten worldwide?",
   "Correct Answer": "30%",
   "Incorrect#1": "50%",
   "Incorrect#2": "10%",
   "Incorrect#3": "85%",
   "Fact": "About a third of the planet’s food goes to waste. It happens in every link of our food supply chain—from the fruit that never makes it off the farm to the vegetables you forgot were in your fridge.",
   "Tip": "TIP: There are lots of things we can do to shop, cook, and eat smarter! "
 },
 {
   "Question": "What food gets tossed the most?",
   "Correct Answer": "Fruits and veggies",
   "Incorrect#1": "Milk",
   "Incorrect#2": "Cereal",
   "Incorrect#3": "Hotdogs",
   "Fact": "45%—almost half of all fruits, veggies, and tubers (like potatoes) are wasted each year! Luckily, there’s lots you can do to make them last longer.",
   "Tip": "TIP: For potatoes, store them in a dark place. If they’ve been around awhile, you can cook them up and freeze in portions. You can roast the skins in some salt, pepper, and oil to make your own crunchy snack. If they start to sprout, you can even cut them up and plant them in your yard! Bananas and apples are some of the most wasted fruits. You can freeze both to use later in baked goods or smoothies. Did you know you can eat the banana peel? You can blend, fry, bake, or boil them. The riper the banana, the sweeter the peel becomes."
 },
 {
   "Question": "What food, when wasted, represents the biggest waste of energy?",
   "Correct Answer": "Beef",
   "Incorrect#1": "Poultry",
   "Incorrect#2": "Milk",
   "Incorrect#3": "Corn",
   "Fact": "It takes about 25 times more energy to produce a calorie of beef than to produce one calorie of corn for people to eat. Animal proteins tend to require more energy—and land and water—to produce than plant proteins.",
   "Tip": "TIP: Shop smart and eat smart! What we eat affects the planet, so it’s important to be aware and consider the impacts of what we eat. You don’t have to stop enjoying the foods you love, but most Americans can reduce their footprint by sticking to the USDA’s nutritional recommendations. You can also make a huge difference by wasting less of what you eat, especially meat, seafood, poultry, and dairy. Learn more about how WWF works with dairy, beef and other protein producers to reduce their environmental impacts."
 },
 {
   "Question": "How much money does the average American spend on food per year that never makes it into meals?",
   "Correct Answer": "$456",
   "Incorrect#1": "$273",
   "Incorrect#2": "$343",
   "Incorrect#3": "$589",
   "Fact": "All told, American consumers waste about $144 billion worth of food each year.",
   "Tip": "TIP: Planning is the key to a successful, sustainable shopping trip. Think through meals in advance and bring a list to cut down on impulse purchases. Don’t shop hungry. Also, make the freezer your friend: freeze bread, meat, and other perishables that you don’t plan to eat immediately."
 },
 {
   "Question": "How much seafood goes to waste in the US?",
   "Correct Answer": "40%",
   "Incorrect#1": "25%",
   "Incorrect#2": "55%",
   "Incorrect#3": "20%",
   "Fact": "Between 40% and 47% of seafood goes to waste in the US. In fact, of all the animal-derived products, seafood goes to waste most often. While some of this loss occurs on the boat, most occurs in supermarkets and home kitchens.",
   "Tip": "TIP: Buy frozen seafood. Most seafood is frozen on the boat and during shipping, only to be thawed for retail display. Purchasing seafood while it’s still frozen and cooking it from frozen helps maintain its quality longer."
 },
 {
   "Question": "Where does most food go to waste in the US?",
   "Correct Answer": "In resturants and at home.",
   "Incorrect#1": "On farms.",
   "Incorrect#2": "During transportation.",
   "Incorrect#3": "In supermarkets.",
   "Fact": "More food is wasted at home and in restaurants than anywhere else along the supply chain. On the bright side, that means we have it within our power to take meaningful steps to protect our planet. By shopping smarter, planning better, and cooking more, we can all do our part—directly—to save food.",
   "Tip": "TIP: Always take home leftovers, consider starting a compost!"
 },
 {
   "Question": "What are good ways to reduce food waste?",
   "Correct Answer": "All of the above",
   "Incorrect#1": "Use wilted fruits for smoothies, and wilted veggies and meat scraps for soup.",
   "Incorrect#2": "Freeze your food.",
   "Incorrect#3": "Write a shopping list and plan your meals.",
   "Fact": "These are all correct, and there are many other ways to reduce your food waste! Get creative!",
   "Tip": "TIP: Support Sustainable Practices: Support businesses and food producers that prioritize sustainable practices and waste reduction."
 },
 {
   "Question": "What percentage of freshwater foes to produce we never end up eating?",
   "Correct Answer": "0.25",
   "Incorrect#1": "0.4",
   "Incorrect#2": "0.15",
   "Incorrect#3": "0.1",
   "Fact": "Food waste is a significant issue, and a substantial portion of freshwater (25%) consumption is associated with producing food that is eventually wasted and never consumed. This inefficiency in the food system has environmental, social, and economic implications.",
   "Tip": "TIP: Instead of throwing away food scraps, consider composting. Compost provides nutrient-rich soil that can be used in gardening and reduces the waste sent to landfills."
 },
 {
   "Question": "How much is spent on the retail value of preventable waste, which includes the cost of the food we never eat?",
   "Correct Answer": "$166 billion",
   "Incorrect#1": "$1 billion",
   "Incorrect#2": "$66 billion",
   "Incorrect#3": "$16 billion",
   "Fact": "Food waste incurs a substantial retail cost of $166 billion, representing the value of the food we never eat. Addressing food waste can lead to significant financial savings while promoting a more sustainable food system and resource conservation.",
   "Tip": "TIP: Save money and reduce food waste by planning your grocery shopping with a well-thought-out list. Stick to the list to avoid unnecessary purchases, ensuring you use up what you buy and minimize food waste."
 },
 {
   "Question": "What is not a commonly wasted food?",
   "Correct Answer": "Frozen Vegetables",
   "Incorrect#1": "Bananas",
   "Incorrect#2": "Milk",
   "Incorrect#3": "Bread",
   "Fact": "Unlike perishable fresh vegetables, frozen vegetables have a much longer shelf life when stored properly in the freezer. They are preserved through freezing, which slows down the spoilage process and helps retain their nutritional value and taste for an extended period.",
   "Tip": "TIP: To minimize food waste and make the most of your groceries, consider incorporating frozen vegetables into your meal planning. Unlike fresh vegetables that may spoil quickly, frozen vegetables have a longer shelf life and retain their nutrients."
 },
 {
   "Question": "What greenhouse gas is produced by food waste rotting in landfill?",
   "Correct Answer": "Methane",
   "Incorrect#1": "Carbon Dioxide",
   "Incorrect#2": "Chloroflurocarbons",
   "Incorrect#3": "Nitrous Oxide",
   "Fact": "Greenhouse gas produced by food waste rotting in landfills is primarily Methane. When organic waste, such as food scraps, decomposes in an oxygen-deprived environment (anaerobic conditions), Methane is generated as a byproduct. Methane is a potent greenhouse gas, with a much higher global warming potential than Carbon Dioxide.",
   "Tip": "TIP: Instead of throwing food scraps in the regular trash, start composting. Composting creates an aerobic environment (with oxygen), which encourages the breakdown of organic matter into nutrient-rich compost. This process minimizes Methane production and provides you with valuable compost for your garden."
 },
 {
   "Question": "How many people could be fed if 25% of our food wasn't wasted?",
   "Correct Answer": "870 million people",
   "Incorrect#1": "1 million people",
   "Incorrect#2": "100 million people",
   "Incorrect#3": "2 million people ",
   "Fact": "If 25% of our food wasn't wasted, approximately 870 million people could be fed. Reducing food waste by a quarter would save a substantial amount of food, making it available to address the nutritional needs of a significant portion of the global population.",
   "Tip": "TIP: If you have excess food that you can't consume, consider donating it to local food banks, shelters, or charities. This way, the food will reach those in need instead of ending up in the trash."
 },
 {
   "Question": "Wasting food wastes what amount of fresh water globally every year?",
   "Correct Answer": "0.25",
   "Incorrect#1": "0.1",
   "Incorrect#2": "0.3",
   "Incorrect#3": "0.4",
   "Fact": "Approximately 25% of fresh water globally is wasted each year due to food waste. This significant loss affects the entire food supply chain, from agricultural production to consumer behavior. Reducing food waste is essential to conserve precious water resources and promote a more sustainable approach to food consumption.",
   "Tip": "TIP: Monitor your food waste to identify patterns and areas for improvement. Raising awareness of wasteful habits can motivate you to be more conscious of your food choices and their environmental impact."
 },
 {
   "Question": "What's the number one way to reduce food loss and waste?",
   "Correct Answer": "Source Reduction",
   "Incorrect#1": "Feed animals",
   "Incorrect#2": "Composting",
   "Incorrect#3": "Landfills",
   "Fact": "The number one way to reduce food loss and waste is \"Source Reduction.\" This refers to taking actions at the source of food production and consumption to prevent or minimize food waste. Source reduction involves better planning, smarter purchasing, and more efficient use of resources to ensure that less food goes to waste in the first place. By addressing the root causes of food waste, source reduction has the most significant impact on reducing overall food loss and waste.",
   "Tip": "TIP: Choose to buy from food companies and producers that prioritize sustainability and employ practices to reduce waste throughout their supply chains. Look for brands that follow eco-friendly packaging, utilize efficient production methods, and commit to reducing food waste."
 },
 {
   "Question": "On average, how much does each individual american waste on food per day?",
   "Correct Answer": "1 pound",
   "Incorrect#1": "1/2 pound",
   "Incorrect#2": "3 pounds",
   "Incorrect#3": "2 pounds",
   "Fact": "On average, each individual American wastes approximately 1 pound of food per day. Food waste is a concerning problem that not only impacts the environment but also represents a significant economic loss.",
   "Tip": "TIP: Serve appropriate portions during meals to avoid overeating and minimize leftovers. If there are leftovers, save them for future meals or repurpose them into new dishes."
 },
 {
   "Question": "How many Americans are food insecure?",
   "Correct Answer": "54 million",
   "Incorrect#1": "28 million",
   "Incorrect#2": "36 million",
   "Incorrect#3": "18 million",
   "Fact": "As of the most recent data available, approximately 54 million Americans are food insecure. Food insecurity is a critical issue that affects individuals and families who lack consistent access to enough nutritious food for an active, healthy life. Addressing food insecurity requires collective efforts from communities, policymakers, and organizations to ensure that everyone has access to sufficient and nutritious food to lead a healthy and fulfilling life.",
   "Tip": "TIP: Donate non-perishable food items or volunteer your time at local food banks. These organizations play a crucial role in providing food assistance to those in need."
 },
 {
   "Question": "What percentge of food waste in America was composted in 2017?",
   "Correct Answer": "0.08",
   "Incorrect#1": "0.28",
   "Incorrect#2": "0.49",
   "Incorrect#3": "0.32",
   "Fact": "In 2017, approximately 8% of food waste in America was composted. Composting involves the decomposition of organic waste, such as food scraps, into nutrient-rich compost that can be used to enrich soil and support plant growth. While composting is an environmentally friendly method to manage food waste, there is still significant progress to be made in increasing composting rates to reduce the environmental impact of food waste in the United States.",
   "Tip": "TIP: To help reduce food waste and contribute to a more sustainable environment, consider starting your own composting practice"
 }
]